pawsitiveliving.ca 2019-03-30

# Privacy Policy - Pausitive Living

Pausitive Living found at https://pausitiveliving.ca (“Website”) is governed by the following privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”).

Pausitive Living respects the privacy of its readers and is ardent about protecting their information. The purpose of this privacy policy is to apprise you of what personally identifiable information we may collect and how it may be used on Pausitive Living. This policy is current, but changes may be made when necessary by updating this page. This statement only applies to this Website.

#### **What Information We Collect and How’s It’s Used!**

♥Information You Voluntarily Submit to This Website: We collect personal information from you such as your name and email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit your information on our website by leaving a comment, using our contact form or subscribing to our newsletter.

♥Information We Collect From Others: We may receive information about you from other sources 3rd party software and sources. You may link your Facebook, Instagram and Google account to your user profile. If you choose to link your Facebook, Instagram and Google account to your user profile, we will receive your name, email address and profile picture associated with that account.

♥Automatically Collected Information: We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the Website. For example, when you use the Website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times you accessed the Websites. We may also collect about actions you take when using the Website, such as linked clicks.

♥Cookies: We may log information using cookies which are small data files stored on your browser by the Website. These files ask permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. We may use both sessions cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until you delete them, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the Website.

#### **How Your Information May Be Used**

We may use the information provided in the following ways:

•To operate and maintain the website;  
•To create your account, identify you as a user of the Website, and customize the Website for your account;   
•To send you promotional information such as newsletters. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out to future mailings;  
•To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, policy updates, or security alerts;  
•To respond to your comments or inquiries;  
•To provide you with user support;  
•To track and measure advertising on the Website;  
•To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorizes or illegal activity.

#### **Third Party Use of Personal Information**

We may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information.

Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policy. This Website uses the following third-party service providers.

Google Analytics: this service tracks website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user action on the Website. Google Analytic may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by this third-party service.

Feedpress: this service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your name and email address for purposes of delivering such communications. Please refer to Feedpress’s [privacy policy](https://feed.press/data-protection) and [GDPR compliance](https://support.feed.press/article/429-gdpr-compliance) for further information.

InLinkz: is a User Generated Content application for creating galleries, also called “LinkUps”, that are embedded in the blog posts. Names and emails are collected but never used or distributed for any reason. Please refer to InLinkz [privacy policy](http://www.inlinkz.com/new/privacy.php).

At this time, your personal information is not shared with any third-party applications. This list may be amended from time to time in the Website’s sole discretion.

Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or personal information without your consent; however, we may disclose or transfer personal information collected through the Website to third parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets, or in connection with any bankruptcy or reorganization proceedings brought by or against us.

#### **Anonymous Data**

From time to time we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising or other uses. An example of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected by cookies.

#### **Public Visible Information**

If you create a user profile on the Website or leave a comment, certain information may be publicly visible. To create a user profile, choose a username and password and input your email address for profile confirmation. Your email address will never be shown or available publicly. You also have the option to add an avatar, profile information and a link to your website.

#### **Cookies**

This website uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same ad banners, customize Website content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Cookies may also be used by third-party services, such as Google Analytics as described herein.

Users may, at any time, prevent the settings of cookies, by the Website, by using a corresponding setting of your internet browser and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an internet browser or other software programs. This is possible on all internet browsers. However, if users deactivate the setting of cookies in your internet browser, not all functions of your Website may be entirely usable.

#### **Advertising**

Display Ads

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies, as noted above.

Retargeting Ads

From time to time, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies such as Facebook, Instagram or Google, in order to market the Website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Website.

Affiliate Program Participation

This Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

Newsletters

On the Website, you may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters send contain tracking pixels. The pixels are embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interest of the user. This behavior will not be passed on to third parties.

**Rights Related to Your Personal Information.**

Opt-Out – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe link in our emails.

Access – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request.

Amend – You may contact us to amend or update your personal information.

Forget – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data by submitting a request.

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for record keeping purposes to complete transactions, or when required by law.

#### **Sensitive Personal Information**

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, religious beliefs, political opinions, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to the Privacy Policy.

#### **Children’s Information**

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 18. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 18 in its database, please contact us immediately and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

Contact Information

At any time, please contact us at lilac@pausitiveliving.ca questions related to this privacy policy.

Last updated: May 10, 2018
